[
  {
    "SlNo": 1,
    "Question": "Sanchar Saathi is an initiative of which organization/Ministry?",
    "Options": [
      "Telecom Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI)",
      "Department of Telecommunications (DoT)",
      "Ministry of Home Affairs (MHA)",
      "Reserve Bank of India (RBI)"
    ],
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 4,
    "Question": "The Sanchar Saathi mobile app was launched in:",
    "Options": [
      "2022",
      "2023",
      "2024",
      "2025"
    ],
    "Answer": 4
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 10,
    "Question": "Which section of Sanchar Saathi creates awareness about telecom safety tips?",
    "Options": [
      "Keep Yourself Aware",
      "Block Your Lost/ Stolen Mobile Handset",
      "Know Genuineness of Your Mobile Handset",
      "Trusted Contact Details"
    ],
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 16,
    "Question": "Which is one of the services offered by the Sanchar Saathi:",
    "Options": [
      "To monitor international communications",
      "To provide mobile service for rural areas",
      "To assist in the tracking of lost or stolen mobile devices",
      "To reduce internet prices"
    ],
    "Answer": 3
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 24,
    "Question": "Citizen can find Wireline Internet service provider in their area by entering:",
    "Options": [
      "PIN Code",
      "Address",
      "ISP name",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "Answer": 4
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 31,
    "Question": "The Sanchar Saathi ensures that a blocked phone:",
    "Options": [
      "Cannot be used on any Indian telecom network",
      "Can only be used for calls",
      "Can only be used for internet",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 35,
    "Question": "If your phone is lost, which 3 steps are recommended as per Sanchar Saathi?",
    "Options": [
      "Block WhatsApp, block SIM, buy new phone",
      "Recharge SIM, call bank, buy new phone",
      "Inform friends, reset phone, inform police",
      "Report to police, block SIM, block handset through Sanchar Saathi"
    ],
    "Answer": 4
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 43,
    "Question": "What happens to mobile connections reported as Not My Number or Not Required on Sanchar Saathi:",
    "Options": [
      "Asking for new mobile connection",
      "flagged for re-verification by the service provider.",
      "change of mobile handset",
      "Nothing happens"
    ],
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 46,
    "Question": "Once a number is reported as Not My Number/ Not required on Know Your Mobile Connections module of Sanchar Saathi, the request cannot be revoked:",
    "Options": [
      "Yes, it can’t revoked",
      "No, it can be revoked anytime",
      "No, it can be revoked by 11:59 PM on the day of reporting",
      "No, it can be revoked within 7 days of reporting"
    ],
    "Answer": 3
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 47,
    "Question": "“Chakshu” module of Sanchar Saathi is used for:",
    "Options": [
      "Blocking mobile numbers",
      "Reporting suspected fraud/spam through calls, SMS, WhatsApp",
      "Paying phone bills",
      "Report IMEI numbers"
    ],
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 52,
    "Question": "If you report a fraud SMS on Sanchar Saathi, what happens?",
    "Options": [
      "SMS is deleted only from your phone",
      "Authorities and telecom operators take action on sender",
      "You are rewarded",
      "Nothing happens"
    ],
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 57,
    "Question": "How can you check the IMEI of your phone to use Sanchar Saathi?",
    "Options": [
      "Dial *#06# on your phone",
      "Only from mobile store",
      "Only by police",
      "Only from Aadhaar"
    ],
    "Answer": 1
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 58,
    "Question": "Which facility of Sanchar Saathi should be used by citizen while purchasing new or second hand phone?",
    "Options": [
      "Block your lost / stolen mobile handset",
      "Know Genuineness of Your Mobile Handset",
      "Chakshu",
      "Trusted Contact Details"
    ],
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 60,
    "Question": "The “Trusted Contact Details” feature of Sanchar Saathi provides:",
    "Options": [
      "Mobile numbers of friends",
      "Official helpline numbers/websites of financial institutions",
      "Recharge offers",
      "Spam numbers"
    ],
    "Answer": 2
  },
  {
    "SlNo": 61,
    "Question": "“Trusted Contact Details” feature of Sanchar Saathi helps in:",
    "Options": [
      "Verifying bank helpline numbers",
      "Recharging prepaid mobiles",
      "Registering new SIM cards",
      "Blocking unknown numbers"
    ],
    "Answer": 1
  }
]